Mss.Ms.Coll.95 Mss.Ms.Coll.95
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Research Subjects (Box 19-85)
  - Iroquoian (Box 32-69)
    - Cherokee (Box 34-36)
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1888, n.d.; ca. 30 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 36)
        Regarding grammar, phonology, etc. Includes photocopy of letter to Gatschet from James Mooney.
      - Cherokee vocabulary on Powell schedule, 1885; ca. 250 pages; Mooney, James, 1861-1921 (Box 36)
        Photocopy of BAE manuscript 1616.
      - Journal of Cherokee Studies, 1976-1978; 9 items; Museum of the Cherokee Indian. (Box 36)
      - Map of the Former Territorial Limits of the Cherokee "Nation of" Indians, 1977; 1 item; Museum of the Cherokee Indian. (Box 36)
        Reprint of 1884 map by C. C. Royce.
      - Cherokee Stories, 1966; 1 item; Spade, Watt, et al (Box 36)
        Printed, Tahlequah, Oklahoma. In the syllabary with English translations.
      - Conversational Cherokee with vocabulary and bibliography, 1966, 1971; ca. 180 pages; Walker, Willard (Box 36)
        Photocopy of typed manuscript. Includes a bibliography by Walker and Janet E. Jordon prepared as a supplement to Murdock's Ethnographic Bibliography of North America.
    - General Iroquois (Box 36-40)
      - Longhouse and Palisade: Northeastern Iroquoian Villages of the Seventeenth Century, 1970; 1 item; Abler, Thomas S., (Thomas Struthers), 1941- (Box 36)
        Offprint of paper presented at the Annual Meeting of the Ontario Historical Society.
      - Jesuit Archives, Quebec and New York, 25 pages; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969 (Box 36)
        Listing of archival materials regarding Iroquoian and Algonquian.
      - Handout for an Iroquois conference, 1993; 1 item; Chafe, Wallace L. (Box 36)
        Language unidentified.
      - Iroquoian Pronominal Prefixes: Comparisons and Implications for Historical Relations among the Tribes, 1 item; [Chafe, Wallace L.] (Box 36)
        Handout for 1972 conference on Iroquois research.
      - The Kahkwas in Seneca Legend, 1995; 1 item; Chafe, Wallace L. (Box 36)
        Handout for Conference on Iroquois Research.
      - Cherokee-Iroquois Symposium, 1959, n.d.; 7 items (Box 36)
        Correspondence and comments regarding papers. Includes a paper by Fred Gearing, "The Rise of the Cherokee State: The 'Mesopotamian' Career to Statehood."
      - Comparative Iroquois Phonology, 1834, 1888, 1938, 1949, n.d.; ca. 60 pp and 6 items (Box 37)
        Photocopies of vocabularies from published works; Zeisberger's "Essay of an Onondaga Grammar"; Barbeau's "How the Huron-Wyandot Language Was Saved from Oblivion"; notes and drafts.
      - Dates and Locations of Meetings, 1 item; Conference on Iroquois Research. (Box 37)
        List of dates for the conference from 1945 through 1995.
      - Schedule for 1969 Meeting, 4 items; Conference on Iroquois Research. (Box 37)
        Includes: list of modern Iroquois communities and ceremonies; conference schedule; list of participants; final announcement of the conference.
      - Schedule for 1995 Meeting, 5 items; Conference on Iroquois Research. (Box 37)
        Schedule, etc. for the conference.
      - Schedule for 1996 Meeting, 3 items; Conference on Iroquois Research. (Box 37)
        Includes conference schedule; population growth for counties in central and western New York from 1810 and 1840 census data; map of the canal system in New York.
      - Iroquois: An Etymology, n.d.; 1 item; Day, Gordon M. (Box 37)
        Offprint from an unidentified journal.
      - Contacts between Iroquois Herbalism and Colonial Medicine, 1941; 2 items; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 37)
        Offprints from the Smithsonian Report for 1941.
      - Deganawidah Legend (part), 1969, n.d.; 1 item; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 37)
        Unidentified English text at least part of which appears to be the Deganawidah legend.
      - Factionalism in American Indian Society, 1952; 2 items; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 37)
        Offprints from Actes du IVe Congres International des Sciences Anthropologiques et Ethnologiques, Vienne, Tome II.
      - Locality as a basic factor in the development of Iroquois social structure, 1949; 1 item; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 37)
        Photocopy of typed document, paper given at AAA symposium.
      - The Lore of the Longhouse: Myth, Ritual, and Red Power, 1970; 1 item; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 37)
      - Masked Medicine Societies of the Iroquois, 1940; 1 item; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 37)
        Offprint from the Smithsonian Report for 1940.
      - The Roll Call of the Iroquois Chiefs: A Study of a Mnemonic Cane from the Six Nations Reserve, 1950; 1 item; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 37)
        Washington, D. C.: Smithsonian Institution, Pub. 3995.
      - Some Questions of Classification, Typology, and Style Raised by Iroquois Masks, 1956; 2 items; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 37)
        Offprint from Transactions of The New York Academy of Sciences, Vol. 18, No. 4.
      - Songs from the Iroquois Longhouse: Program Notes for an Album of American Indian Music from the Eastern Woodlands, 1942; 1 item; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 37)
        Washington, D. C.: Smithsonian Institution, Pub. 3691.
      - Symposium on Local Diversity in Iroquois Culture, 1951; 1 item; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 37)
        Washington, D. C.: Smithsonian Institution, BAE Bulletin 149.
      - An Elm Bark Canoe in the Peabody Museum of Salem, 1949; 1 item; Dodge, Ernest Stanley; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 37)
        Offprint from The American Neptune, Vol. IX, No. 3.
      - Symposium on Cherokee and Iroquois Culture, 1961; 1 item; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Gulick, John (Box 37)
        Washington, D. C.: Smithsonian Institution, BAE Bulletin 180.
      - Iroquoian Chronological Summary, 1986; 1 item; Foster, Michael K. (Box 37)
      - Sociolinguistic Profile of the Longhouse Iroquois at Six Nations Reserve, 1971; 1 item; Foster, Michael K. (Box 37)
      - Base and Affix Dictionary for Iroquoian Languages, 1989; 1 item; Foster, Michael K.; Michelson, Karin; Woodbury, Hanni (Box 37)
        Mimeo of paper for symposium at the Conference on Iroquois Research.
      - Cultural Persistence Among the Modern Iroquois, 1958; 1 item; Freilich, Morris (Box 37)
        Offprint from Anthropos, Vol. 53.
      - Field Studies of the Iroquois in New York State and in Ontario, Canada, 1936; 1 item; Hewitt, J. N. B., (John Napoleon Brinton), 1859-1937 (Box 37)
        Offprint from "Explorations and Field-Work of the Smithsonian Institution in 1936."
      - Fieldwork among the Iroquois Indians of New York and Canada, 1932; 1 item; Hewitt, J. N. B., (John Napoleon Brinton), 1859-1937 (Box 37)
        Offprint from "Explorations and Field-Work of the Smithsonian Institution in 1932."
      - The Requickening Address of the Iroquois Condolence Council, 1944; 1 item; Hewitt, J. N. B., (John Napoleon Brinton), 1859-1937 (Box 37)
        Offprint from Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences, Vol. 34, No. 3.
      - Some Esoteric Aspects of the League of the Iroquois, 1917; 2 items; Hewitt, J. N. B., (John Napoleon Brinton), 1859-1937 (Box 37)
        Offprint from Proceedings of the Nineteenth International Congress of Americanists, Washington, December, 1915.
      - Status of Woman in Iroquois Polity before 1784, 1933; 1 item; Hewitt, J. N. B., (John Napoleon Brinton), 1859-1937 (Box 37)
        Offprint from the Smithsonian Report for 1932.
      - Iroquois Place Names in Vermont, 1957; 1 item; Huden, John C. (Box 38)
        Article included in Vermont History, Vol. XXV, No. 1.
      - Elements of Comparative Philology - The Iroquois Languages, 1862; 1 item; Latham, Robert Gordon, 1812-1888 (Box 38)
        Photocopies of selected pages pertaining to Iroquoian languages.
      - Altered States of Consciousness in Northern Iroquoian Rituals, 1973; 1 item; Lex, Barbara W. (Box 38)
        Ditto of typed document.
      - Articles for HNAI, n.d.; 13 items; 4 folders; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 38)
        "Iroquoian Historical Linguistics" and "Iroquoian Languages"-notes various drafts for the Handbook of North American Indians.
      - Chart of Iroquoian archeological sites (after MacNeish), n.d.; 2 items; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 38)
      - Expressions of Relationship in Iroquoian, 1976; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 38)
        Handout for talk at the Yale Linguisitcs Club.
      - The Grammar of Relationships in Iroquoian, 1976, ca. 1979, n.d.; ca. 50 pages; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 38)
        Notes, drafts, handouts for "Expressions of Relationship in Iroquoian."
      - Iroquoian Languages, n.d.; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 38)
        Offprint from HNAI.
      - Iroquoian Morphology, n.d.; ca. 400 pages; 2 folders; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 38)
        Draft of Ph.D. Dissertation.
      - Iroquois-Cherokee Linguistic Relations, n.d.; 4 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 38)
        Offprints from BBAE 180. Includes FGL's paper and comments on his paper by Mary R. Haas.
      - Iroquois Church Service Books, 1875, ca. 1982, n.d.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 38)
        Includes: "Selections from the Psalms and Hymns, According to the use of the Protestant Episcopal Church" Translated into Ohawk and Iroquois (New York: Whittaker, 1875); "Ionteriwaienstakwa: Ne Kariwiioston Teieiasontha" (n.d.); notes.
      - Iroquois lists, n.d.; 6 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 38)
        Swadesh basic vocabulary, etc.
      - Iroquois Place-names in the Champlain Valley, 1960; 12 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 38)
        Offprints.
      - Iroquois word lists, n.d.; 7 items; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 38)
        Oneida, Onondaga, Cayuga, Seneca, Tuscarora, and Cherokee.
      - The Kahkwa Synonymy, 1994-1995; 4 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 38)
        Abstract of article regarding the meaning of 17th century Iroquois names of the Niagara region. Includes letter from Blair Rudes.
      - Miscellaneous Iroquois materials (Seneca, Tuscarora, Cherokee), n.d.; 13 items; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 39)
        Miscellaneous notes.
      - Miscellaneous vocabulary and phonological notes, ca. 1951; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 39)
      - Notes on comparative Iroquoian phonology, n.d.; 2 items; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 39)
      - Notes on "Indians", 4 items; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 39)
        Names, some with addresses, of several Tuscaroras and a Mohawk.
      - Notes on Iroquoian historical linguistics, n.d.; ca. 225 pp and 1 notebook; 2 folders; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 39)
        Notes and drafts.
      - Notes on Iroquois cosmology myth, n.d.; 19 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 39)
      - Notes on names, n.d.; ca. 100 cards and slips, 8 other items.; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 39)
        Includes place names, and some personal names.
      - Notes on Onondaga and Tuscarora Grammar, 17 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 39)
      - Notes on Seneca and Cayuga, 1 item; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 39)
        One notebook.
      - Notes on Tawiskala?, n.d.; 15 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 39)
      - Outline for comparative Iroquoian Grammar, n.d.; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 39)
      - Research projects, 1948-1950, n.d.; 16 pages; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 39)
        Dissertation proposal, fieldwork proposals, reports on fieldwork.
      - Sonagrams of unidentified language, n.d.; ca 40 pcs.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 39)
      - Thesis notes, n.d.; ca. 125 pages; 4 folders; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 39)
        Thesis notes for comparative Iroquoian morphology.
      - Thesis prospectus, n.d.; 8 pages; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 39)
        Thesis prospectus for comparative Iroquoian mophology.
      - Unidentified notes on Iroquoian, 1971, n.d.; 4 items; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 39)
      - Vocabularies and Lexico-statistic lists for Tuscarora and Oneida, 7 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 39)
      - Iroquois Crafts, 1945; 1 item; Lyford, Carrie A., (Carrie Alberta) (Box 40)
        Iroquois Crafts, Department of the Interior, United States Indian Service, Education Division, Printing Department, Haskell Institute.
      - Up-streaming Bruyas, 1972; 1 item; Michelson, Gunther (Box 40)
        Probably a handout for a paper for the 1972 Conference on Iroquois Research.
      - Handouts for Conference on Iroquois Research, 1993, 1 item; Michelson, Karin (Box 40)
        Includes: "Active Verbs" regarding unidentified language (possibly Oneida); "Incorporation of English nouns into Oneida verbs."
      - Distribution and Number (Northern Iroquoian), 1995; 1 item; Mithun, Marianne (Box 40)
        Handout for paper at the 1995 Iroquois Conference.
      - The Future Is to Come, 1993; 1 item; Mithun, Marianne (Box 40)
        Handout for paper at the 1993 Iroquois Conference.
      - Barbeau's Wyandotte, 1996; 1 item; Pearson, Bruce L., b. 1932 (Box 40)
        Handout for paper at the 1996 Iroquois Congerence.
      - An in situ Hypothesis for the St. Laurence Iroquoians, 1972; 1 item; Pendergast, James F. (Box 40)
        With handouts for 1972 Iroquois Conference.
      - The Kakouagoga or Kahkwas: An Iroquoian Nation Destroyed in the Niagra Region ca. 1640, 1994; 1 item; 7 pages; Pendergast, James F. (Box 40)
        In Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, Vol. 138; photocopies of pages showing maps.
      - Bibliography of the Iroquoian Languages, 1888; 1 item; Pilling, James Constantine, 1846-1895 (Box 40)
        Washington, D. C.: Smithsonian Institution.
      - Iroquois Indians: A Documentary History, 1984; 1 item; Research Publications, inc. (Box 40)
        Brochure describing a microform collection of 8,000 documents.
      - The Chance Horizon: An Early Stage of Mohawk Iroquois Cultural Development, 1952; 1 item; Ritchie, William A. (Box 40)
        Albany: The University of the State of New York.
      - Affricates and Fricatives in Iroquoian, 1988-1989; 3 items; Rudes, Blair A. (Box 40)
        Drafts of the article and notes from Rudes to FGL.
      - Iroquoian Accent and Vowel Length, 1992; 198 pages; 2 folders; Rudes, Blair A. (Box 40)
        Draft of book-length work. Includes letter from Rudes to FGL.
      - Iroquoian Vowels, 1995; 1 item; Rudes, Blair A. (Box 40)
        Offprint from Anthropological Linguistics, Vol. 37.
      - Suggested Improvements in the Reconstruction of the Proto-Northern Iroquoian Morpho-phonological System, 1973-1974; 2 items; Rudes, Blair A. (Box 40)
        Draft and final version of Rudes' MA thesis.
      - Myths of the Iroquois, n.d.; 2 items; Smith, Erminnie A., (Erminnie Adele), 1836-1886 (Box 40)
        Original and carbon of typed document.
      - Often mis(?) interpreted quotes, 1995; 1 item; Snyder, Gary, 1930- (Box 40)
        Part(?) of handout for 1995 Iroquois Conference.
      - The Supplemental Treaty of Buffalo Creek (1842), [1995]; 1 item; Spencer, Ambrose; Spencer, John C., (John Canfield), 1788-1855 (Box 40)
        Handout for 1995 Iroquois Conference.
      - Ethnometaphysics of Iroquois Ritual, n.d.; 1 item; Tooker, Elisabeth, 1927- (Box 40)
        Offprint from Symbols and Society: Essays on Belief Systems in Action, Southern Anthropological Society Proceedings, No. 9.
      - Archaeological Evidence for Seventeenth Century Iroquoian Dream Fulfillment Rituals, 1968; 1 item; Tooker, Elisabeth, 1927-; White, Marian E. (Marian Emily), 1921-1975 (Box 40)
        Offprint from Pennsylvania Archaeologist, Vol. XXXIV, No. 3-4.
      - Notes on Oneida-Cherokee Comparisons, n.d.; 8 pages; Witthoft, John, 1921- (Box 40)
        Prefixes.
      - Iroquois Conference Handout, 1987; 2pages; Woodbury, Hanni (Box 40)
        Form of dictionary entries for unidentified language.
      - Handout for "Diplomatic transcription: Pi(c)quet's Creed, 1-4, 1993; 4 pages; Wright, Roy (Box 40)
    - Huron (Box 41)
      - Lost Huron Map, 1972; 1 item; Goddard, R. H. Ives, III (Box 41)
        Ditto handout for 1972 Conference on Iroquois Research.
      - A Collection of John Steckley's Papers on Iroquoian Linguistics, 1996; 1 item; Pendergast, James F. (Box 41)
        "First Published in 'Arch Notes' the OAS Newsletter over the Period 1982-1995."
      - The French Presence in Huronia: The Structure of Franco-Huron Relations in the First Half of the Seventeenth Century, 1968; 1 item; Trigger, Bruce G. (Box 41)
        Offprint from The Canadian Historical Review, Vol. XLIX, No. 2.
      - The Historic Location of the Hurons, 1962; 1 item; Trigger, Bruce G. (Box 41)
        Offprint from Ontario History, Vol. LIV, No. 2.
      - The Huron-Iroquois of Canada, a Typical Race of American Aborigines, 1885; 9 pages; Wilson, Daniel, Sir, 1816-1892 (Box 41)
        Photocopy of selected pages of vocaublary.
      - Grammar of the Huron Language, n.d.; 19 pages; Wright (Box 41)
        Apparently extracts from a larger document, typed manuscript.
    - Mohawk (Box 41-42)
      - Mohawk, 1949; 105 pages; 2 folders; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969 (Box 41)
        Photocopies of Barbeau's fieldnotes.
      - Noun Incorporation in Mohawk, 1972; 1 item; Bonvillain, Nancy (Box 41)
        Handout for the 1972 Conference on Iroquois Research.
      - Radical Words of the Mohawk Language, with their Derivatives, 1863; 1 item; Bruyas, Rev. James, (Jacques) (Box 41)
        Grammatical and lexicographical treatise published as Sixteenth Annual Report of the Regents of the University of the State of New-York, Albany: Comstock and Cassidy, Printers. In French.
      - The Mohawk Iroquois, 1949; 1 item; Carse, Mary Rowell (Box 41)
        Printed in Bulletin of the Archeological Society of Connecticut, No. 23.
      - Mohawk notes, n.d.; 4 items; Cory, Rev. David M.; Dialo, Louise (Box 41)
        Notebook of English-Mohawk vocabulary. Also includes list of Mohawk numbers from Rev. Hawley (1809), letter introducing FGL in search of a Mohawk "informant," and a small hand-written Mohawk dictionary and phrase book.
      - The Mohawk Vocabularies of C. C. Trowbridge, 1972; 1 item; Frisch, Jack A. (Box 41)
        Handout for paper given at the 1972 Conference on Iroquois Research.
      - Iroquois Cosmology: Mohawk, [1903]; 200 pages; Hewitt, J. N. B., (John Napoleon Brinton), 1859-1937 (Box 41)
        Photocopy from the Twenty-First Annual Report of the Bureau of American Ethnology, 1899-1900.
      - Topics in Mohawk Grammar, 1988; 284 pages; 3 folders; Hopkins, Alice W. (Box 41)
        Draft of dissertation at The City University of New York.
      - Mohawk-1958 (Caughnawaga), 1 item; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 42)
        Partially filled notebook containing vocabulary.
      - Mohawk (Caughnawaga) - notes, n.d.; ca. 95 pages; 2 folders; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 42)
        Handwritten and typed notes on vocabulary, etc.
      - Mohawk (Minnie Diabo) fieldnotes, 1951; 1 item; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 42)
        One small notebook.
      - Mohawk Notes from 1951-1952, 11 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 42)
        Handwritten notes primarily phonetics and phonology.
      - Mohawk Dialects and Their History, 1971, n.d.; 3 items; Michelson, Gunther (Box 42)
        Copies of typed documents: "Mohawk Dialects and Their History," and "Mohawk Idioms" versions of the paper.
      - Notes for a Mohawk Dictionary, 1994; 1 item; Michelson, Gunther (Box 42)
        Mohawk-English and English-Mohawk, "Based on field work in Kahnawake, P. Q. since 1961"
      - Mohawk manuscript, n.d.; 3 pages; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939 (Box 42)
        Handwritten copy of Sapir's manuscript.
      - Wampum: Source and Mother of Mohawk Ascendency, 1994; 3 pages; Snyder, Gary, 1930- (Box 42)
        Dissertation prospectus.
    - Oneida (Box 42-63)
      - General (Box 42-47)
        - The Two Feminine Genders in Oneida, 1983; 1 item; Abbott, Clifford (Box 42)
          Draft of article sent to FGL as referee by David S. Rood for IJAL.
        - Oneida pedagogical materials, 1995, n.d.; ca. 50 pages; 2 folders; Anonymous (Box 42)
          Grammar, conversations, etc.
        - Oneida Writing Systems, n.d.; 4 pages; Anonymous (Box 42)
          Five systems used for writing Oneida.
        - Oneida notes, 1950; ca. 60 pages; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969 (Box 42)
        - Kwa?ko:li or The Whip-poor-will, 1975; 1 item; Cornelius, Melissa (Box 42)
          Children's story.
        - Corporate Charter and Constitution, 1936-1937; 3 items (Box 42)
          "Constitution and By-laws for the Oneida Tribe of Indians of Wisconsin" (1 copy) and "Corporate Charter of the Oneida Tribe of Indians of Wisconsin of the Oneida Reservation" (2 copies).
        - Correspondence - Oneida Verb Morphology, 1952-1953; 24 items (Box 42)
          Correspondence (primarily with Irving Rouse) regarding FGL's Oneida Verb Morphology.
        - The Story of Deganawida, 1950, 1971; ca. 925 pages; 8 folders; Elm, Demus (Box 42-43)
          Recited in Oneida. Includes FGL's transcripts of the recording, some translation, text in interlinear form (Oneida and English). Includes duplicates for some material. Consultant's name also given as "Damas."
        - Transcription, 1973; ca. 110 pages; Elm, Demus; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 43)
          Transcription of June 29, 1971, recording by Mr. Elm. Transcribed by FGL with Mr. Elm's help.
        - Four Ways of Spelling Oneida, n.d.; 17 pages (Box 43)
          Parts of typed documents on spelling "Oneida" and pedagogical material.
        - From Project Display, 1940, n.d.; ca. 25 items (Box 43)
          Lists of names, "interesting facts about the Oneida language," etc.
        - How Indians Came to America, 5 pages (Box 43)
          Text in Oneida, one with interlinear free translation. From a file folder labeled "Oneida-How Indians Came to America-Transcr and Transl."
        - Letter to J. D. McLean, 1915; 4 pages (Box 43)
          From the Council of the Oneidas of the Thames regarding the history and current affairs of the Oneidas who sought the protection of the British government in moving to Canada rather than Wisconsin. Photocopy of document in the Public Archives of Canada.
        - Grammatical notes, n.d.; 25 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 43)
          Grammatical notes primarily on verb morphology.
        - Lexical Index, 4 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 43)
          Oneida vocabulary items indexed by letter-number text identifier, most with English translation.
        - Lexical Work, 1964; 4 items; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 43)
          Includes: letter to FGL from Joseph Greenberg requesting vocabulary lists; partially completed list for Oneida.
        - Notes on Oneida Work, n.d.; 5 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 43)
          Part of a typed letter detailing procedures, processing, etc. for collecting texts during the WPA project.
        - Oneida lexico-statistic list, n.d.; 11 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 44)
        - Oneida notes, etc., 1950, 1975, n.d.; ca. 50 pp, 1 offprint; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 44)
          Primarily parts of the Deganawida story. Includes offprint of William N. Fenton, "The Lore of the Longhouse: Myth, Ritual and Red Power," Anthropological Quarterly, Vol. 48, No. 3 regarding two Onondaga versions of the story.
        - Oneida Phonology - Draft of M. A. Thesis, n.d.; ca. 150 pp.; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 44)
        - Oneida Phonology - notes, n.d.; 40 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 44)